EDWARD KONG

eddiekong13@gmail.com | (732) 325-5055 edwardkong.github.io New York City

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Software and Application Developer with 1.5+ years of professional experience involving all aspects of the SDLC and Agile methodology. Proficient in key programming fundamentals and data skills, specializing in Java, Python, SQL, as well as various front-end and big data technologies and principles.

EXPERIENCE

Lifion by ADP New York, NY

Application Developer

Mar 2019 – Mar 2020

- Designed efficient and scalable data architectures for large sets of client data
- Integrated data sets into utilization metric visualizations and extrapolated data to improve worker-manager communication channels
- Migrated pre-existing data to new database architecture using SQL scripts
- Utilized inhouse Lifion MVC platform to create modular and flexible HR applications
- Automated testing and processes using Java and Python scripts
- Oversaw release handoffs and provided ad-hoc support and feature improvements as per client requests

Invidi Technologies Corporation

Princeton, NJ

Software Developer Intern

June 2018 – Aug 2018

- Guided product owners and senior management on use cases and practicality of Apache Hadoop & Kafka
- Configured a three node Hadoop cluster to simulate data warehousing across an HDFS
- Benchmarked data stream pipeline to reach low latency and extremely high throughput (~300K msgs/s)
- Created Kafka Stream scripts to perform stateless transformations on advertising impression messages in real-time by aggregating and sorting fields such as location, demographic, response, etc.
- Presented programs and findings as a proof of concept to justify the integration of data analytics and insights

Princeton University Princeton, NJ

Technical Support Specialist

May 2017 - Sept 2017

- Acted as a Level II technician for The Woodrow Wilson School of Public and International Affairs
- Performed client-facing maintenance on software such as R Project, Eclipse, Microsoft Office, etc.
- Managed a university-wide database of users and equipment

EDUCATION

New York University, Tandon School of Engineering

New York, NY

Bachelors of Science in Computer Science

Sept 2014 – Dec 2018

PROJECTS

Standout

- Suite of applications built on the Lifion platform revolving around improving employee engagement
- Managers can personalize their management style based on employee's worker-personality profile, anonymous check-ins, and engagement pulses for individuals, dynamic teams, or direct reports
- Applications demonstrated at HR tech conferences, winning several awards and recognition

Gradr

- Multipurpose web application for students, parents, and tutors involved in private education and tutoring
- Users can assign, submit, grade, and leave feedback on assignments, tutors, and courses
- Built on Django (Python), HTML/CSS, and Javascript

ADDITIONAL SKILLS & INTERESTS

Proficient: Machine Learning, Pandas, Data Modeling, Tableau, C++, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Hadoop, Kafka, Git **Familiar:** Spark, C, Docker, Kubernetes, MySQL, MongoDB, Django, Flask, Selenium, Node.js, XML, Gradle **Interests:** Music & Music Production, Art/Visual Design, Film, Cooking, Sports(NBA, NFL, UEFA, ATP)